| João Costa |
|--|
| Porto, Porto, Portugal poaoartursilvacosta@gmail.com 912866937 🚡 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jo%C3%A3o-costa-8b112110b/ 📤 https://joao-costa.vercel.app/ |
| SUMMARY |
| I'm an IT professional with 7 years experience in the areas of banking, |
| Digital Marketing and E-commerce. |
| I love building things that live on the web and I'm passionate about |
| using technology to build a better user experience for my customer. I'm |
| highly motivated to provide legendary service to my customers and |
| team mates |
| EXPERIENCE |
| SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER |
| RealFevr January 2023 - Present, Porto , Portugal |
| • Developed and launched the NFTs Marketplace with multi-chain support, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and a 20% growth in daily transactions. (organya.world) |
| Developed and deployed a Liquidity and Staking Platform (staking.realfevr.com) |
| Mentored and provided code reviews for junior developers, resulting in a 30% improvement in overall code quality and efficiency |
| • Spearheaded application-wide performance enhancements, integrating efficient coding practices and modern front-end technologies, which culminated in a 40% uplift in key |
| performance indicators such as load times, interactivity, and conversion rates. |
| • Increased test coverage by 75% by writing automated test scripts for critical frontend features |
| FRONTEND LEAD DEVELOPER |
| Migso-P3cubed January 2021 - April 2023, Porto , Portugal |
| • Oversaw a team of 5 developers in successfully building and deploying multiple planning and project management applications to support PMO activities |
| • Spearheaded the creation of a custom state management library akin to Redux, leveraging the Context API, to enhance application performance by 20%, thereby streamlining workflow and improving user experience for enterprise-level applications. |
| Developed and managed a robust component system library using Storybook, ensuring consistent design and functionality across projects. |
| • Spearheaded client-side application architecture enhancements and executed performance optimizations to elevate user experience and efficiency. |
| WEB DEVELOPER |
| Natixis January 2017 - December 2021, Porto , Portugal |
| • Developed Angular and React applications and interfaces to support daily operations of KYC (Know Your Customer) process |
| • Enhanced user experience and compliance efficiency by developing intuitive Angular and React-based applications for the KYC process, supporting over 5,000 daily users and |
| reducing manual entry time by 30%. |
| EDUCATION |
| ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING |
| Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto • Porto , Portugal • 2016 |
| SKILLS |
| React 18 |
| RxJs |
| TypeScript |
| Tailwind CSS |
| React Hooks |
| Mocha |
| Cypress |

SASS
HMTL 5
mobX
NextJs 14
Express
NodeJs
TRPC